...
My planet Arrakis is so beautiful
when the sun is low.
Rolling over the sands...
you can see spice in the air.
...
At nightfall. the spice harvesters land.
The outsiders race against time
to avoid the heat of the day.
...
They ravage our lands
in front of our eyes.
Their cruelty to my people
is all I've known.
...
These outsiders. the Harkonnens.
came long before I was born.
By controlling spice production.
they became obscenely rich.
Richer than the Emperor himself.
...
Our warriors couldn't free
Arrakis from the Harkonnens.
but one day.
by Imperial decree. they were gone.
Why did the Emperor choose this path?
And who will our next oppressors be?
...
It's good you're up early.
Your father wants you in full dress
before the Emperor's Herald arrives.
Full dress?
Military?
Ceremonial.
Why do we have to go
through all this
when it's already been decided?
Ceremony.
Mm.
Thank you.
If you want it. make me give it to you.
Use the Voice.
Mom. I just woke up.
Give me the water.
The glass can't hear you.
Command me.
...
Give me the water.
Almost.
Almost?
Bene Gesserit skills
take years to learn. Paul.
Mm-hmm.
You look tired.
More dreams?
No.
Extreme temperatures
and treacherous weather events
make life outside the cities
of Arrakis truly hostile.
with sandstorms powerful enough
to cut through metal.
Only the native tribes
known as the Fremen
have adapted well enough to survive.
Preferring to inhabit
the remotest regions of Arrakis.
the Fremen share the deep desert
with the giant sandworms
known to the Fremen as Shai-Hulud.
Long exposure to spice
has given the tribe
their characteristic blue eyes.
the Eyes of Ibad.
Little else is known of the Fremen.
except that they are dangerous
and unreliable.
Fremen attacks make spice harvesting
extremely hazardous.
For the Fremen.
spice is the sacred hallucinogen
which preserves life
and brings enormous health benefits.
For the Imperium.
spice is used by the navigators
of the Spacing Guild
to find safe paths between the stars.
Without spice.
interstellar travel is impossible.
making it by far
the most valuable substance
in the universe.
...
Smile. Gurney.
I am smiling.
How much will it cost them.
traveling all this way
for this formality?
Three Guild Navigators.
A total of 1 .46 million.
62 solaris. round trip.
By the grace of Shaddam IV
of House Corrino.
ascendant to the Golden Lion Throne
of Padishah Emperor
of the Known Universe.
I stand before you
as Herald of the Change.
We are witnessed by members
of the Imperial Court.
representatives of the Spacing Guild
and a sister of the Bene Gesserit.
The Emperor has spoken.
"House Atreides shall immediately
take control of Arrakis
and serve as its steward."
Do you accept?
We are House Atreides.
There is no call we do not answer.
there is no faith that we betray.
The Emperor asks us
to bring peace to Arrakis.
House Atreides accepts.
Atreides! Atreides! Atreides!
Your seal.
So. it's done?
It's done.
How was it?
Stabilizers are too loose.
We'll dial it in.
Thank you. my friend.
Got it.
Duncan.
My boy.
Hey. Hey.
Paul. my boy.
So. you're going to Arrakis tomorrow.
With the advance team.
Yes. I'm going to Arrakis tomorrow
with the advance team.
I'd like you to take me with you.
You would?
Well. that's too bad. 'Cause no.
Duncan.
Are you trying
to get me court-martialed?
What's going on?
Can I trust you with something?
Always. You know that.
...
I've been having dreams.
About Arrakis and the Fremen.
...
Okay.
So?
I saw you.
With the Fremen.
Ah.
So. I do find them.
There you go. That's a good
omen right there. right?
Lanville!
I saw you lying dead.
Fallen in battle.
It felt like if I had been there.
you'd be alive.
First off. I'm not gonna die.
You're not taking me seriously.
That's why you want
to come with me. Listen.
Dreams make good stories.
but everything important
happens when we're awake.
'Cause that's when
we make things happen.
Look at you. Put on some muscle?
I did?
No.
Hey.
See you on Arrakis. my boy.
...
Father. I'd like to ask
to join Duncan Idaho
on his scout mission
to Arrakis tomorrow.
I've studied the Fremen language.
I'd be an asset.
Out of the question.
You'll travel in a few weeks to Arrakis.
like the rest of us.
I've been training my whole life.
What is the point if I'm not allowed
to face some actual risk?
You know why. Paul.
You're the future of House Atreides.
And Grandfather fought bulls for sport!
Yes.
And look where that got him.
I need you by my side.
When we get to Arrakis.
we'll face enormous danger.
What danger?
The Fremen? The desert?
Political danger.
The Great Houses
look to us for leadership.
and this threatens the Emperor.
By taking Arrakis from the Harkonnens
and making it ours.
he sets the stage for a war
which would weaken both houses.
But if we hold firm.
and tap the true power of Arrakis.
we could be stronger than ever.
What does that mean?
Mining spice.
keeping the Fremen in their place?
We'd be no better than Harkonnens.
No.
By making an alliance with the Fremen.
That's what I've sent
Duncan Idaho to arrange.
Here on Caladan.
we've ruled by air power and sea power.
On Arrakis. we need
to cultivate desert power.
I want you sitting in on my Council.
Learn what I do.
What if I'm not. Dad?
Not what?
The future of House Atreides.
...
I told my father
I didn't want this either.
I wanted to be a pilot.
You never told me that.
Your grandfather said.
"A great man doesn't seek to lead.
He's called to it. and he answers."
And if your answer is no...
you'll still be the only thing
I ever needed you to be...
my son.
I found my own way to it.
Maybe you'll find yours.
In their memory...
give it a try.
...
Don't stand
with your back to the door.
How many times do we have to tell you?
I could tell it was you
by your footsteps. Gurney Halleck.
Someone
might imitate my stride.
I know the difference.
Are you the new Weapons Master?
With Duncan Idaho gone.
I must make do as best I can.
Choose your blade.
I've had quite a day. Gurney.
Give us a song instead.
That's rude.
...
Come on.
Old man.
...
Ah. the slow blade
penetrates the shield.
...
I guess I'm not in the mood today.
Mood?
Yeah.
What's mood to do with it?
You fight when the necessity arises.
no matter the mood.
Now fight!
...
Come on!
I have you.
Aye.
But look down. my lord.
You'd have joined me in death.
I see you found the mood.
...
Will it be that bad?
You don't get it. do you?
You don't really understand
the grave nature
of what's happening to us.
For 80 years.
Arrakis belonged to House Harkonnen.
80 years of owning the spice fields.
Can you imagine the wealth?
Your eyes.
I need to see it in your eyes.
You never met Harkonnens
before. I have.
They're not human. they're brutal!
You have to be ready.
...
Lord Baron.
Rabban.
The last of our ships have left Arrakis.
It's done.
Very good.
Uncle. how can we let this happen?
How can the Emperor...
.. .take everything
we've built
and give it to that Duke?
How?
Don't be too sure it's an act of love.
...
What does he mean?
When is a gift not a gift?
The Atreides' voice is rising.
and the Emperor is a jealous man.
A dangerous. jealous man.
...
Paul.
Paul. wake up.
What's wrong?
Get dressed and come with me.
What is this?
The Reverend Mother
Gaius Helen Mohiam is here.
She was my teacher
at the Bene Gesserit school.
She's now Truthsayer
to the Emperor himself.
She would like to meet you.
Why?
She wants to know about your dreams.
How does she know about my dreams?
And why is Dr. Yueh here?
He only needs a moment.
Hello. young master.
Your mother asked me
to check your vitals.
What's happening?
...
His heart
is strong as ever. my lady.
...
Paul...
Who are you?
Defiance in the eyes.
Like his father.
Leave us.
You must do everything
the Reverend Mother tells you.
You dismiss my mother
in her own house.
Come here.
Kneel.
How dare you use the Voice on me?
Put your right
hand in the box.
Your mother bade you obey me.
...
I hold at your neck the Gom Jabbar.
A poison needle.
Instant death.
The test is simple.
Remove your hand from the box
and you die.
What's in the box?
Pain.
No need to call the guards.
Your mother stands behind that door.
No one would get past her.
Why are you doing this?
An animal caught in a trap
will gnaw off its own leg to escape.
What will you do?
...
Silence.
I must not fear.
...
Fear is the mind-killer.
Fear
is the little death
that brings obliteration.
...
And I'll face my fear and I'll permit it
to pass over me and through me.
...
And when it has gone past...
I will turn the inner eye
and see its path.
And where the fear has gone.
there will be nothing.
Only I will remain.
Enough.
...
Like sifting sand through a screen.
we sift people.
If you had been unable
to control your impulses.
like an animal.
we could not let you live.
You inherit too much power.
What. because I'm a duke's son?
Because you are Jessica's son.
You have more than one birthright. boy.
Jessica?
You've been training him in the Way.
Tell me about these dreams.
I had one tonight.
What did you see?
A girl.
On Arrakis.
Have you dreamt of her before?
Many times.
Do you often dream things that happen
just as you dreamed them?
Not exactly.
Goodbye. young human.
I hope you live.
Did you have to go that far?
You chose
to train him in the Way.
in defiance of our rule.
He wields our power.
He had to be tested to the limits.
So much potential. wasted in a male.
You were told to bear only daughters.
But you. in your pride.
thought you could
produce the Kwisatz Haderach.
Was I wrong?
You're lucky he didn't die in that room.
If he is The One.
he has a long way to go.
His Sight is barely awakened.
and now he goes into the fire.
But our plans are measured in centuries.
We have other prospects
if he fails his promise.
Do you see so little hope?
On Arrakis. we have done
all we can for you.
A path has been laid.
Let's hope he doesn't squander it.
...
Paul.
What does it mean?
That I could be The One?
You heard.
The Bene Gesserit serve
as powerful partners
to the Great Houses.
but there's more to it.
You steer the politics of the Imperium
from the shadows.
I know.
You don't know everything.
For thousands of years.
we've been carefully crossing bloodlines
to bring forth--
The One?
A mind...
powerful enough
to bridge space and time.
Past and future.
Who can help us into a better future.
We think he's very close now.
Some believe he's here.
All part of a plan.
...
Shield.
"My lungs taste the air of Time.
Blown past falling sand.. ."
...
Thufir Hawat.
Young master!
How does it feel
to walk on a new world?
Exciting. to say the least.
My lord.
How are you. old friend?
My advance team has secured the city.
We're still smoothing out
a few rough spots.
My lady.
Lisan al-Gaib!
...
Lisan al-Gaib! Lisan al-Gaib!
Lisan al-Gaib!
Don't be fooled by the welcome.
They follow their old masters' rules.
Mandatory attendance.
That's Harkonnen love out there.
...
Atreides!
Atreides! Atreides! Atreides!
Atreides! Atreides!
Let's get you out of the sun.
The heat can kill in this place.
...
They were pointing at us.
What are they shouting?
Lisan al-Gaib.
"Voice from the Outer World."
It's their name for "messiah."
It means the Bene Gesserit
have been at work here.
Planting superstitions.
Preparing the way. Paul.
These people
have waited for centuries
for the Lisan al-Gaib.
They see you.
they see the signs.
They see what they've been
told to see.
We're good to go.
Shield Wall.
Protects the city from the weather
and the worms.
...
The locals call
the big one the Hand of God.
Well. the Hand of God
is wreaking havoc
on our comms system.
It's so quiet.
Yeah.
That's what worries me. too.
There's the spaceport
and that plume of dust there
is the spice refinery.
Our two most vulnerable points.
I want you guarding them.
If we can't refine spice
and ship it off-world.
we're dead here.
My lord.
The sun's getting too high.
We need to seal the doors.
...
What do they say
about this hellhole again?
"To shower. you scrub your ass
with sand." my lord.
That's what they say.
Candidates
for a housekeeper. my lady.
What is your name?
Shadout Mapes. my lady.
The rest of you may go.
Thank you.
Shadout.
It's an old Chakobsa word.
"Well-dipper."
...
You know the ancient tongues?
I know many things.
I know that you have a weapon
concealed in your bodice.
...
If you mean to harm me.
I must warn you.
whatever you're hiding.
it won't be enough.
The weapon is meant as a gift
if you are truly The One.
Do you know this?
It's a crysknife.
Do you know its meaning?
...
It's a maker...
A maker of the deep desert.
When you have lived
with prophecy for so long.
the moment of revelation
is a shock.
Lisan al-Gaib.
The mother and the son.
It is yours.
Tooth of Shai-Hulud.
...
Lisan! Lisan al-Gaib!
Lisan al-Gaib! Lisan al-Gaib!
Hello.
You shouldn't be out here
at this hour of the day.
They're out here.
Hmm. Fremen pilgrims.
They don't care about heatstroke.
I didn't know date palms
could even be found out here.
Oh. these aren't indigenous.
They can't survive without me.
Each one of these
drinks every day
the equivalent of five men.
Twenty palm trees.
A hundred lives.
Should we remove them?
Save the water?
No. no. no.
These are sacred.
Old dream.
The largest and most dangerous
organism on Arrakis is the sandworm.
capable of reaching
400 meters in length.
To avoid making rhythmic noises.
which attract the sandworms.
the Fremen cross desert spaces
using the sandwalk.
a dance-like motion
with irregular rhythm
which emulates the natural
sounds of the desert.
What scant plant life
exists on Arrakis
is thanks to the Fremen.
who have cultivated
deep-rooted terranic plants
such as saguaro. burrobush.
sand-verbena and incense bush.
The shepherd's tree has
the deepest documented roots.
stretching more than 450 feet deep.
...
These plants cling to life
in a parched. nutrient-poor landscape.
...
It's a hunter-seeker.
The operator must be nearby.
...
The Harkonnen agent
was cemented
into that hole six weeks ago.
Ran the hunter-seeker
through a water pipe
inside the walls.
Sire. I failed you today.
There's no excuse.
You have my resignation.
You would deprive us
of your talents at this time?
Sire. my honor demands--
They tried to take the life of my son!
I don't give a damn about your honor.
You want absolution?
Go catch some spies.
Your Grace.
The thing must leave.
You can speak without fear.
Our pet doesn't understand
your language.
Get out.
It understands.
Activate silence.
...
It must never be known.
There's no satellites
over Arrakis.
The Atreides will die in the dark.
On that matter.
Duke Leto Atreides
means nothing to our order.
But his wife is under our protection
and by extension. her son.
Allow them the dignity of exile.
...
House Harkonnen would never dream
of violating the sanctity of your order.
I give you my word.
We will not harm them.
If the Duke's son lives...
No Atreides will live.
My lord. you gave your word
to the witch.
She sees too much.
I said I would not harm them.
And I shall not.
But Arrakis is Arrakis.
And the desert takes the weak.
My desert.
...
My Arrakis.
My Dune.
Your first strategy meeting.
Paul Atreides.
who catches hunter-seekers
in his bare hands
like a hero of old.
...
Thanks
for the humiliation. old man.
Gotta keep an eye on you.
Attention!
Let's get started.
Thufir. Operations.
I secured a copy
of the Harkonnens' account books.
...
The Harkonnens were taking
10 billion solaris
out of here every year.
"They shall suck
of the abundance of the seas.
and the treasure hid in the sand."
We won't see profits
like that for a while.
Not with the equipment they left us.
How bad is it?
These are spice silos.
We're meant to fill every crate.
All of them?
Every 25 standard days.
Harkonnen sabotage slows us down.
But who's meant to arbitrate?
Isn't there a Judge of the Change
to oversee the transition?
Who did the Emperor appoint?
Dr. Liet Kynes. Imperial Ecologist.
Been here 20 years.
Eccentric. from what I'm told.
I want to see these
harvesting fields myself.
I wouldn't recommend it. my lord.
Have this Judge of the Change
accompany us.
A meeting's long overdue.
And we'll get a bit
of Imperial protection.
A hostage.
I love it.
Hmm.
He's here. my lord.
...
Take care of them.
They are friends.
Duncan!
Ah ! My boy!
...
I swear you're getting taller.
Well. you smell much worse.
For four weeks. I lived with the Fremen.
Hidden in the desert.
in a community called a sietch.
Stilgar. the leader of that sietch.
has come with me to meet you. sire.
This sietch. how is it hidden?
It's underground.
Arrakis is filled with caverns.
How big was the place?
I'd say 10.000 people.
And there are hundreds of sietches.
Millions of Fremen.
You were right.
The Harkonnen estimate
was 50.000 on the whole planet.
The Fremen watched me
search for them for days.
I never saw them.
Finally. they sent
a warrior out to kill me.
And I gotta tell you.
I have never come so close to dying.
There's no finer fighter
in the Imperium.
They fight like demons.
Desert power.
Duncan.
Well done.
Thank you. my lord.
Sire.
Their leader has a knife
he won't surrender. sire.
It's a crysknife.
It's sacred to his people.
Let him pass.
Stop there.
Hey! Hey!
Mm.
Stilgar.
Welcome.
Sir. I respect the personal dignity
of any man that respects mine.
...
Hmm.
Hold.
Thank you. Stilgar.
for the gift of your body's moisture.
We accept it in the spirit
in which it was given.
...
I'm glad you've come.
I believe your people and mine
have much to offer one another.
No. no. you are Outworlders.
You come here for the spice.
you take it. giving nothing in return.
That's true.
I know you've suffered
at the hands of the Harkonnen.
Name what you want.
If it's in my power to grant.
I'll give it and ask for nothing.
Mm. I ask for this.
Do not seek our sietches.
Do not trespass in our lands.
The desert was ours
long before you came.
So. come and dig your spice.
but when you have it.
go back to this side of the Shield Wall
and leave the desert to the Fremen.
You will address the Duke
as "my lord" or "sire."
Gurney. just.. .
just a moment.
The Emperor
has given me Arrakis as my fief
to rule and protect.
I cannot promise
not to travel into the desert
if duty compels me.
But your sietches will be yours forever.
And you will never be hunted
while I govern here.
That's very honorable.
I must go. That's all
I have to say to you.
Won't you stay?
We would honor you.
Honor requires that I be elsewhere.
...
I don't like him.
Our plan bears fruit.
But it will take time?
Yes.
It will take time.
Here. this is for you.
It's a paracompass.
The moons here
have a magnetic field. so...
a simple compass needle
won't point north.
Takes a clever piece
of clockwork to sort it out.
The Fremen make these?
And stillsuits. and sand compactors.
and all kinds of ingenious things.
What the hell
is a sand compactor?
That's a sand compactor.
...
My God. man. you've gone native.
You admire them.
I do.
They're fierce but loyal.
They're attuned to the desert.
Part of it.
It's part of them.
You wait till you see it.
It's beautiful out there.
Sunrise warning.
all workers.
Temperature today
will reach 140 degrees.
We are currently 90 degrees.
and in 10 minutes.
we will hit 120 degrees.
Last warning call.
...
The Judge of the Change. sire.
Dr. Liet Kynes.
My lord Duke.
Welcome to Arrakis.
You're the Imperial Ecologist.
Thank you for the stillsuits.
They are of Fremen make.
The best.
With your permission. sire.
I must check
the integrity of your suit--
Whoa.
It's all right.
Dr. Kynes.
we're in your hands.
A stillsuit is a high-efficiency
filtration system.
Even this early in the morning.
you wouldn't survive two hours
without one of these.
It cools the body
and recycles
the water lost to sweat.
Your body's movements
provide the power.
Inside the mask. you'll find a tube
to allow you to drink
the recycled water.
Mm.
In good working order.
your suit won't lose
more than a thimbleful of water a day.
Most impressive.
Let's have a look at you. lad.
You've...
worn a stillsuit before?
No. this is my first time.
Your desert boots are fitted
slip-fashion at the ankles.
Who taught you to do that?
It seemed the right way.
...
Are you Fremen?
I am accepted
in both sietch and village.
Now. come and see the spice sands
on which your livelihood depends.
...
What would you do
if your ornithopter went down out here?
You wouldn't want
to go down out there.
It's worm territory.
Dust cloud.
I see it.
That's one of your harvesters.
...
You can see the spice
scattered over the surface.
A rich spice bed
by the color.
If you get a little higher.
you'll have a better view.
You see these spotter aircraft
looking for wormsign.
Wormsign?
A sand wave
moving toward the crawler.
Worms travel deep but get closer
to the surface when they attack.
If you are patient.
we should see one.
A worm always comes?
Always. They're drawn
by rhythmic noises.
Why don't we just
shield the crawlers?
A shield's a death sentence
in the desert.
It attracts the worms
and drives them into a killing frenzy.
Is that a worm?
Big one.
You have good eyes.
Calling crawler Delta Ajax niner.
Wormsign warning. Acknowledge.
Who calls Delta Ajax niner?
Over.
They seem pretty calm about it.
Unlisted flight.
Imperium business.
Wormsign north and east of you.
3.7 kilometers.
Delta Ajax niner.
this is Spotter One.
Wormsign confirmed.
Stand by for contact fix.
Worm is on intercept course
to your position.
Contact in five minutes.
So. what happens now?
They'll call a carryall
to lift the crawler.
They'll harvest right up
to the last minute.
Calling carryall Alpha Zero.
Ready for docking sequence.
Contact five minutes. Over.
Anybody got a visual
on the carryall?
There it is.
This is carryall Alpha Zero
to Delta Ajax niner.
Approaching from your east.
Correcting altitude
and preparing docking equipment.
Copy. Alpha Zero.
Initiating docking sequence.
T-5.
Copy that.
Prepare to be airborne
in 30 seconds.
Docking sequence initiated.
Brace yourselves.
...
Alpha Zero. we're short
one point of contact.
What is going on?
It's one of the anchors.
It's dead.
Shit.
Carryall unable to proceed.
Unable to lift without that anchor.
All call! All call!
Any carryall in the sector.
please respond!
Spotter One.
give us an update. Over.
Hydraulics are dead.
We won't make it.
You have to evacuate.
Contact in four minutes.
Try it again!
How many men on that crawler?
Crew of 21.
Our ships can take six each.
That's still three short.
We'll find a way.
This is Duke Leto Atreides.
We're coming down to extract
the crew of Delta Ajax niner.
We'll set down on the west.
Shield generators
weigh 100 kilos each.
Yes. Gurney.
have our escorts throw out
the shield generators.
Yes. sire.
And. Paul. I want you
at the back of the thopter.
Guide them in.
Delta Ajax niner.
put seven men each in my ships now.
...
Contact in two minutes.
Getting close. guys.
We better abandon ship now.
...
Where are they?
Sir. there's protocol
for a reason.
If we take one step out there.
we're as good as dead.
Besides. we've got a full load of spice.
-We can't just leave it.
Damn the spice!
I want every man off that crawler now!
...
Hey!
Seven over here. seven over there.
Go! Go! Go!
...
Kwisatz Haderach.
Kwisatz Haderach awakes.
...
Hurry! Get on!
It's here!
Paul!
I recognize
your footsteps. old man.
Get up!
Let's go!
What's the matter with you?
Come on ! Let's go!
Run!
...
Hey!
Bless the Maker and His Water.
Bless the coming and going of Him.
May His passage cleanse the world
and keep the world for His people.
...
Hey!
You cannot take such risks.
Yes. sir.
You have responsibilities.
I... I'm sorry. sir.
It won't happen again.
Go.
Dr. Kynes.
You saw it.
With your own eyes. It's plain to see.
Everything they've left us
is in shambles.
We've been set up to fail.
That carryall was just old.
The desert isn't kind to equipment.
You know what will happen
if I don't get spice
production back on track.
...
I'm not here to take your part.
Arrakis has seen men like you
come and go.
Take good care of your family.
The desert's not kind
to humans either.
Spice is a psychoactive chemical.
You seem to be sensitive.
You'll be fine.
Thank you. Dr. Yueh.
That wasn't an allergic reaction.
I had a vision.
My eyes were wide open.
What did you see?
...
Kwisatz Haderach.
You can see.
It's confusing.
I thought I saw my death.
only it wasn't.
I know a knife is important. somehow.
Someone will hand me a blade.
but I don't know who.
or when. or where.
Some things. though. are crystal clear.
I can feel it.
I know you're pregnant.
You can't know that.
I barely know that.
It's only been a few weeks.
...
Atreides legions
are the finest in the Imperium.
Trained by Gurney Halleck
and Duncan Idaho.
...
Just so.
Three battalions.
As agreed.
...
There is something
you need to know about Paul.
No.
Don't think I want to know.
Ever since you brought him
before your Reverend Mother.
he hasn't been the same.
He's distracted.
Jessica. you gave me a son.
And from the moment he was born.
I never questioned you.
I trusted you completely.
Even when you walked in shadows.
Now I'm asking you this one thing.
If anything happens...
will you protect our son?
With my life.
I'm not asking his mother.
I'm asking the Bene Gesserit.
Will you protect Paul?
Why are you having these thoughts?
Leto. this is not you.
I thought we'd have more time.
Have a good night.
Master Paul.
Good night. Dr. Yueh.
You need to sleep.
No.
Not like that.
...
I should have married you.
Hawat. Security.
Security.
...
Sir. Sir.
The shield's come down.
...
God in heaven.
Get everything with guns
off the ground ! Go!
...
Go! Go! Go!
With me! With me!
...
Atreides!
Sardaukar!
...
I'm sorry. my lord.
But I've made a bargain
with the Baron.
...
Why?
I had no choice.
The Harkonnens have my wife. Wanna.
They take her apart like a doll.
I will buy her freedom.
And you are the price.
For Paul. I will do what I can.
And you
will kill a man for me.
I'm going to replace your peg tooth.
If you bite down hard.
this tooth will crush.
Breathe out. and you will
fill the air with poison.
It will be your last breath.
But if you choose your moment well.
it will also be the Baron's.
...
Paul.
To hell. dogs!
...
I've never had a highborn.
You?
Bene Gesserit ain't all highborn.
She's highborn
enough for me.
Let's feed the kid to the worms.
And give her a long goodbye.
Don't you dare touch my mother.
Don't talk.
...
Remove her gag.
Shut up.
...
Remove her gag.
Kill him.
Set us free.
...
Stop!
Cut the rope.
Give me the knife.
...
Your pitch was too forced.
It's a fremkit.
...
I serve only one master.
His name is Shai-Hulud.
...
There are jet flares behind us.
Paul. We're not high enough!
...
I must not fear.
Fear is the mind-killer.
Fear is the little death
that brings obliteration.
...
See the friend.
The mystery of life
isn't a problem to solve...
but a reality to experience.
A process that cannot
be understood
by stopping it.
We must move
with the flow of the process.
We must join it.
We must flow with it.
Let go.
...
We chased them
into a Coriolis storm.
Winds at 800 kilometers an hour.
Nothing survives such a storm.
They're dead.
It's a certainty.
...
So. it's done. Finally.
Send word to Giedi Prime
to begin selling our spice reserves.
But slowly.
We don't want the price to fall.
You have no idea how much it cost me
to bring such a force to bear here.
Now I only have one requirement.
Income.
So. squeeze. Rabban.
Squeeze hard.
Yes. Uncle.
And the Fremen?
Kill them all.
...
We're above 5.000 meters.
As soon as we land.
run for the rocks.
...
And breathe through this.
Now we have to find the Fremen.
Are you good?
Yeah.
...
Paul...
Don't be frightened.
Even a little
desert mouse can survive.
Don't be frightened.
You'll need to face your fears.
A friend...
A friend will help you.
Follow the friend.
You have much to learn.
And I will show you
the ways of the desert.
Come with me.
...
The sietch where Duncan lived
is somewhere off that way.
I can see
greenery over there.
There.
That means Fremen live there.
We'll cross after dark.
That's how the Fremen do it.
We're about to enter
worm territory.
We can't walk like regular humans.
If we do. we're dead.
We'll have to walk like the Fremen do.
It's called a sandwalk.
At least according
to the filmbooks back home.
Yeah. Yeah. okay.
Okay. Follow me.
Do the same moves.
...
I think this is the right direction.
It's close by.
Let's get out of here.
Wait.
It's drum sand.
...
Run.
Go! Go!
...
It's a thumper.
Someone set off a thumper.
...
Paul ! Run!
How big are they?
That was insane.
...
Someone called it.
Do not run.
You will only waste
your body's water.
Hold.
Stilgar.
Hey!
You know me. I was there
when you came
to my father's Council.
Oh.
This is the Duke's son.
Why are you waiting?
We need their water.
This is the boy
I told you about.
We can't touch him.
...
They are weaklings.
Jamis.
That was a brave crossing they made
in the path of Shai-Hulud.
He does not speak
or act like a weakling.
Nor did his father.
My thumper saved his life.
Go back to reason. Stilgar.
He's not The One.
...
We have powerful friends.
You help us off-world. to Caladan.
you will be well rewarded.
What wealth can you offer
beyond the water
in your flesh?
Hmm...
The boy is young.
He can learn our ways.
He may have sanctuary.
But the woman is untrained...
and too old to learn.
...
Back. you dogs.
She'll cut my throat.
Why didn't you say
you were a weirding woman?
And a fighter?
Conversation ran short.
Peace. woman.
Peace.
I judged hastily.
...
I would not
have let you hurt my friends.
They say you're the Mahdi.
But you look like a little boy.
You chose the hardest way up.
Follow me.
...
Give it to me.
You will have your own maula pistol
when you've earned it.
Give it to me.
Chani. take charge of the newcomers.
See that they are safe
on the journey. Let's go.
I will not have them.
Jamis.
I have spoken. Be still.
You talk like a leader.
But the strongest leads.
She bested you.
I invoke the amtal.
You may not challenge
a Sayyadina.
Then who will fight in her name?
Jamis. don't do this.
Don't. The night is fading.
Then the sun will witness this death.
Where is her champion?
I accept her champion.
...
Paul Atreides must die...
for Kwisatz Haderach to rise.
Don't be frightened.
Don't resist.
When you take a life.
you take your own.
...
I don't believe
you're the Lisan al-Gaib.
But I want you to die with honor.
This crysknife was given to me
by my great aunt.
It's made from a tooth of Shai-Hulud.
The great sandworm.
This will be a great honor.
for you to die holding it.
Where is the Outworlder?
Jamis is a good fighter.
He won't let you suffer.
Chani...
Um...
...
Never mind.
May thy knife chip and shatter.
You should welcome my blade.
This world will kill you.
Quicker this way.
...
Do you yield?
The boy doesn't know our rule.
...
There's no yielding
under the amtal rule.
Only death is the test of it.
...
Is he toying with him?
No.
Paul has never killed a man.
...
Kwisatz Haderach.
Climb up. Rise.
...
You're one of us now.
A life for a life.
Come with us to Sietch Tabr.
No.
Paul needs to get off-world.
You must have ways. You have smugglers.
you have ships.
No.
You have...
The Emperor sent us to this place.
And my father came.
not for spice.
not for the riches.
but for the strength of your people.
My road leads into the desert.
I can see it.
If you'll have us.
we will come.
...
Desert power.
This is only the beginning.